[Music]
so
do
[Music]
so
manulife and china bank
two companies you can trust two top
institutions in the financial industry
teammates partners working together to
handle every aspect of your finances
from day to day to your future plans
personalized to your story
so you're ready for life's every twist
and turn
we have you covered starting with your
kids dreams
to providing a secure future for your
family
working to build your wealth and
ensuring your wealth
works for you always with you in
sickness and in health
through the best times and the worst all
just for you
let us be your partner manulife china
bank life
life with a plan let us help you get
started
today
1920.
here 100 years ago men
of courage and vision founded china bank
to help a community of struggling but
worthy merchants and traders
achieve their dreams
they were driven by an impeccable code
of trust
and respect through the hard times
and the good times that's how
china bank successfully partnered with
four
five generations of loyal clients
today china bank keeps pace with
evolving technology
while remaining grounded on integrity
and prudence
china bank celebrating the past
embracing the future times change
but values remain
what makes an organization successful
is it being a top layer in sales and
market share
acquiring new customers or generating a
healthy income
and net profit it's no secret that to
achieve all of these
a company needs its most valuable asset
people most businesses have one
or more senior personal whose experience
skills and knowledge are vital to
achieving company goals
losing them can have adverse effects
including missing company targets
investing in human and monetary
resources to find a replacement
and reduced confidence among
stakeholders
like investors partners and customers
one solution to protect your business
from all of these
is key man insurance but what exactly is
a key man insurance
a key man is someone who contributes
significant service or talent
to the organization and its customers
and the keyman insurance protects you
against the sudden loss of this key
person
by providing enough liquidity to ensure
continuity of business and aiding the
company
and recovering from the loss many firms
ensure their premises equipments and
goods
against fire theft and flood
but many missed the opportunity to
insure their company
against the loss of key people who
helped run it successfully
manulife china bank life can provide you
with the innovative key man solutions to
serve your company's needs with key man
insurance
will protect your company from the
possible loss of your key people
to ensure your continued success
contacts manulife china bank life now
to help you get started
good afternoon everyone i'm ronnie
austria welcoming you to manulife china
bank's
business resilience in time of covid19
webinar
as mcbl celebrates their 13th year in
the industry today
we have brought together speakers to
talk about reinventing your business
to stay relevant and create value for
customers
during these trying times during the
past
six months we have also heard a lot
about resilience
and today we make business resilience
more tangible and achievable
through the solutions that we offer and
to make this afternoon even more worth
your while we are raffling off
ten thousand pesos worth of sodexo gift
certificates
so make sure you stay for that to
welcome you all
and officially open our program let us
watch this video from
china bank's chief finance officer mr
patrick cheng good afternoon
thank you for attending this webinar
presented by
mcbl mcbl
is a combination of two entities my new
life
and china bank normally we give you
financial advice advice about day-to-day
banking
advice about loans advice about how to
grow your money through investments
and very important right now advice
about protection
today we present to you people who are
creative
innovative and will also talk to you
about how they pivot
in their business strategies so sit back
relax and enjoy the talk thank you
and stay safe
thank you mr chang now let's get right
to the program by introducing
our first speaker he is a successful
entrepreneur and proud owner of the
highlighted chinese restaurant huang fu
and coal and ash international systems
corporation
a supplier distributor of customs
furniture
metal filings aluminum partitions grease
flooring
and seating he is also china bank's
brand and
he will share practical tips and
learnings on how to adapt
and change business strategies quickly
ladies and gentlemen please welcome mr
richard yap
[Music]
mr yap i think you're on you
sorry hi good afternoon everyone and
thank you for having me here
as a former ambassador of my life and
now of china bank
it is an honor for me to be here with
you today and
first of all i'd like to say happy 13th
anniversary to manulife china bank life
um more power to you and more years
and more anniversaries to come well
uh first we'll start off some of you may
know me as an actor
and as a model but first of all i was
really a businessman when all this
started i graduated
in business and i was always in business
i was in corporate life before
but i also had i was also running a
business i was
formerly a franchisee of ciao king and
now we have our own restaurants which
are wang fu
and i also handle coal and ash which is
a systems
furniture supplier um i'm here to share
some practical tips
of uh being resilient in the times of
kovid right now so uh
let me go right to my uh
what you call that um sharing of my tips
uh let's see the first slide
okay um since this pandemic started
there was an ecq which meant that uh
everything was locked down we weren't
allowed to go out
and all the malls were closed all the
shops were closed our restaurants were
closed
so how can we survive in times like this
when we can't even sell our products
so what we did is we had to innovate
uh we had to bring our our products to
our customers
that's where this comes in we have to
meet your customers where they are
so instead of waiting for people to come
since uh we weren't allowed
people weren't allowed to go out we had
to bring our products to them we had to
bring our food to them
um that's why we had to do take
out and delivery at that time there was
not
takeout was not even an option because
people were not allowed to go out
so delivery was the only way to go but
we didn't have our own delivery staff
so we had to collaborate with grab food
food panda
to do our deliveries for us but
at that time uh there were so many
people who were using uh
these apps uh to deliver all these items
that they needed all the essential items
that we were having a hard time
delivering our products
so we also had to innovate and
set up our own delivery teams so
this helped us a lot because delivery is
only really 30
of the business in a restaurant so
that is what helped us survive during
this very trying times
and it also helped us grow our brand
because instead of just limiting it to
where our stores are located
now we had the option to deliver even to
farther areas
because we could deliver our food to
them so
this widened our services to other areas
this is where
online presence comes in we had to build
our online presence also because
people who were not familiar with our
brand
since they don't go to the malls that we
are where we are
they didn't know that uh they could
experience the type of food that we were
serving so we had to build our online
presence we had to be
more visible on social media facebook
instagram uh youtube we had to do all
these things
and um so that people would be aware
that they could come to us and they
could order food from us
even though they're far far away so this
gave us a little bit of uh relief
because uh
it helped our sales so
this uh offset what was uh
subtracted by people not being able to
come to our restaurant
okay so next slide please
yeah and
secondly we had to optimize our
workforce
we have to cross utilize your staff to
stay profitable
how we did this is uh we have they have
to multitask
because at that time there was also no
public transportation
so a lot of our staff had a lot of
trouble come getting into coming into
work
and not everybody could come in also
because like in our restaurants
um there's no dine in so we didn't need
any weight staff
so uh what we had to do since there was
a no dine-in policy at that time
we had to think about saving the jobs of
our other
non-essential staff which was the wait
staff at that time
so everyone would be able to survive and
not just a company
so we reassessed our business uh options
and we trained our staff to do other
jobs so they had to multitask they had
to
do other things like uh the wait staff
we had to train them so that they would
also
deliver our food at first it was only
for
the nearer areas but some of the wait
staff had their own motorcycles as well
so we trained them to be able to to
deliver also
like you know to be like the grab food
riders or the
grab you know food panda so
we had to train our own team and make
make us uh
set up our own delivery staff so that we
could also
not rely on just the other apps as well
so you know these are we have you really
have to reassess
what it is that your business needs are
at this time
because uh it's not all that all the
time that things will remain
uh the same there's a constant change
especially now this
this has been really uh
this has been really trying for everyone
okay after that
uh we have to revisit our customer
experience the next slide please
so we revisit our customer experience we
expected changes in
consumer preferences because uh there
there were a lot of people who didn't
have jobs also
they didn't have uh uh they were trying
to be thrifty
so we found out that you know um people
were ordering for sharing
so now that everyone is at home they
were ordering not only for themselves
but also for sharing for their whole
family
so we had to come out with uh
people wanted to get the best value for
their money
so this is where our offers came in uh
we offered affordable packages or promos
so that they would be able to share
and find that the the products that they
bought were at a very
reasonable price and it was really value
for money
especially now like right now we have
the mooncake promo
um it's uh it's a package of
some a lot of food items that you can
buy
which is which comes out cheaper than
buying it a la cart
so but in order to give the same quality
and dining experience
we had to ensure that there was a safe
environment not only for our customers
but also for our staff
which means that we had to make sure
that everyone was safe
nobody was sick in our staff and that
because uh if one person gets sick
we you know we could we could
give that sickness to everyone who who
taste our food
so we had all of them tested our
restaurants were sanitized
and um of course we had to improve our
takeout packaging
if our takeout packaging was just basic
when we were
uh when this this pandemic started now
we had to make
ensure that it was safe it was uh before
during and up till the delivery when it
arrives to the customer
the packaging must be very
it must not be flimsy you know so
we had to make sure that all these
things were
were done so that we could deliver our
food with the same quality as
when you eat it in the restaurant okay
so uh
i think that should be everything that
uh
we've done in the last few months um it
has helped us a lot and um
it has helped us survive so uh
um i guess i hope that all the other
restaurants will also learn from the
tips that we gave
thank you very much
thank you mr yap for all the practical
tips that you share
as we now face a different landscape of
course we will see more of you later
if you have questions just type it in in
our q a box
and our speakers will answer it during
the panel session
in the meantime we will raffle off 2 000
pesos worth of sodexo
gift certificates let's see our first
travel winner
is congratulations mr brian
christian bernardo our representative
from mcbl will get in touch with you
on how you can claim your prize once
again congratulations
of course we have more sodexo gc's up
for grabs
shortly so make sure you stay tuned for
that
now i have the honor of introducing our
second speaker
he is a globally renowned multi-awarded
furniture designer
and manufacturer whose mastery pieces
were featured in several hollywood films
and tv shows
such as ocean's 13 maid of honor
total recall csi miami
suits and kdramas oh my venus and
cunning single lady
actor brad pitt is also known to own
several of his works
he once designed a five-piece collection
inspired by star wars icons created in
collaboration with disney
he is the recipient of multiple
international accolades including
the first design for asia award ever
given to a filipino designer
and the first ever asian designer of the
year award
ladies and gentlemen please welcome mr
kenneth copenhuev
hello
good afternoon everyone and the happy
anniversary
to china bank um to manulife china bank
life thank you so much for inviting me
here
i'm currently in cebu right now i've
been here since
lockdown and i want to share with you a
small journey
of what we were doing before the
pandemic
and right after what what we did
to stay creative and resilient and i'd
like to share with you
some slides
see here
down here let me just see hope this
works
okay yeah perhaps
um many of you
haven't uh heard of what i do so i'd
like to share with you
um yeah i'd like to share with you what
i do and
and my journey so i'm i'm a furniture
manufacturer based in
in cebu and these are some of my works
i currently sell and manufacture under
my own
name and i sell all over the world many
of you have pro
probably know me because of this bed
which
brad pitt and angelina jolie when they
were still together
used to uh sleep in and uh
this bed has been a lot of videos and uh
it's been
in a lot of uh magazines and perhaps
uh without this bed i wouldn't be
speaking in front of you here today
so we currently sell around the world
through our own
stores through our own showrooms and uh
these are some of the collections which
uh
made me known and no famous all over the
world
this is my first design called the yin
and yang and so
i was very known for this open very very
transparent
furniture and this is this is the
peacock chair
which won an award in las vegas a few
years ago it beat
3 000 other entries and won the best
chair
so it's my interpretation of the
traditional filipino peacock chair this
is called the tilt
made out of wood it's one of the most
difficult pieces to do
um at one and a wired also in new york
for
craftsmanship and this is of course the
bloom
which is inspired by the flower
comes in several colors and this is
something that was very very different
because it's not the traditional woven
filipino
product and this is always very creative
to me design should be all about
fantasy imagination and when i was young
i always wanted
i always imagined what it would be like
to have circus performers
performing and hanging everywhere in
your house so i made my own life-size
sculpture called limbo so
inspiration comes from everywhere and we
were very
inspired before kovid like grass
blades of grass became the inspiration
for the yoda chair
which i'm sure many of you know
even a bowl of noodles became the
inspiration for
the noodle chair and
this is my own version of sheep
i asked myself what made the sheet
beautiful it's just furry
hair this this big thing this mass of
hair
and so i took away strip everything
that was not essential made my own
version of sheep
and i put it back in its natural habitat
where it belongs
so life was very creative even a coke
can became the inspiration for the lola
chair which won another award in hong
kong
for the best asian design award
normally this award is given to
traditional
industrial giants like sony apple and
hyundai and in 2005 they gave it to a
filipino
for aratan chair and i collaborate also
with disney and i made the star wars
collection
uh last earlier last year and this was
the first time that disney allowed
another designer
to put its name beside its brand so it's
star wars
and kenneth cabon these are some of the
pieces in that star wars
collection so i designed other things
also
like a bamboo bicycle very different
things my own
tricycle and i wanted to romanticize and
upgrade
the tricycle which we all love this has
cup holders
this is gps and uh yeah it's
it's very light and it's it's kind of
still filipino but
reinterpreted in a totally different way
yeah designed also my own car which has
been in a cover in a lot of books about
sustainability made out of bamboo
and carbon fiber so
and of course one of the hallmarks in my
career was i designed the setting
for the apec world leaders meeting
inspired by the rice
terrorists so life was really very
creative
uh before coving you know i
designed also the airport in together
with
other architects and this one in fact
the world's most beautiful airport award
those of you who've been there have seen
how beautiful the interiors is it's like
it's like the uh inside of a hull of a
boat it's all made of wood
i designed also a bamboo church
i collaborated with an architect with
here in cebu and it's also got a
nomination for a
world architecture award and then
kovid king and so the challenge was how
to stay
creative how to stay resilient you know
the factory is closed
it couldn't sell our furniture anymore
and life just suddenly stopped
now creativity is is not
easy when you're working from home
because you can't
just expect it when you're having a zoo
meeting creativity comes to you
as a burst of inspiration anywhere you
know when you're eating
when you're sleeping and you just can't
call everyone to say hey i've got a
great idea let's all meet
it doesn't happen and so and
it was very very difficult for employees
to work from home because
home to a lot of people means sleep
means rest
you know and to now put to expect them
to work from a place
which has always been there to them a
place of comfort was very difficult so
our productivity went
really low so we devised a way you know
um okay before that this is my this is
my office
at home um it's uh
and uh i get bored easily so i i put
things
around it every once in a while i i take
a break
to to enjoy the things around and i keep
on moving places
um yeah like this is another one i set
up also
another corner of the room which has a
window
so it's important when you're working
from home that when you're bored in one
space that you you move you know trying
to find
maybe inspiration or different
perspective on
life depending where you look at so this
is what we did with our
employees we have this called start of
day and end of day monitoring
so they are all expected to fill this
out at the start of the
which is simple number one to find first
is to explain how you're doing
second if you have any issues in the
family with a focus on
health the well-being third is to state
your location the example here is on the
right this is actually a text message
from a leadership team the fourth is the
task what you plan to do
during the day and five any if you have
any concerns
and the at the end of the day they're
supposed to message
the same thing to their supervisor or to
me
yeah and we found that this has been
very very
productive this our productivity jumped
you know
almost threefold because now we were
able to monitor what they were doing
you know and it's also helped them
discipline themselves
in addition to that we couldn't sell
anymore physically in our showrooms
back then so we had to strengthen our
online presence we didn't have much
content because
we weren't really prepared for it and we
couldn't anymore photograph
our furniture in spaces if there was a
lockdown we couldn't come together
so we started to reinvent ourselves and
do everything digitally this is an
example
of an actual table which we photographed
and we built
these settings around it so we all had
to
work now to create this digital rendered
settings meaning these are not real
these are all
created in a computer uh and like for
example this chair here this is called
the papillon it's like a hammock
and we put them now in these
environments this is still
work in progress because it doesn't look
surreal but you
get the idea this for example it's a
design of mine called apollo it's like a
tree house
and we put it now in its setting these
are not real these are all rendered
settings but we try to make them
as real as possible so this is what we
had to do
and this is me again trying to find
trying to
still stay creative in the house so
trying to move around
in different corners of the house which
is not always
easy so i also
tried to pick up new skills so i went on
youtube and i started to paint i started
to draw
i started to build these little settings
for my
my furniture uh this is the voyage bed
which you've seen it was always inspired
by a boat
so i tried to put it in a boat and this
will become the storyboards for our
future
catalog this for example is a design of
mine called little people
they're actually two people that we
build and make it into screen so imagine
a kind of like gulliver's uh travel
where this this guy wakes up and he's
tied down by all these
little people you know this is harry
which you saw i tried to imagine
a boy a shepherd boy leading all these
harry's
my ship up the mountains this will
become the pegs for our new
catalog and we started to become very
very creative these are all
actually new images uh using this is a
halo lamp it's a it's actually a lamp
and on the side on the other side is
actually a mirror frame
and we tried so we tried to create
experiment
so we had a lot of time at home so the
my call to them was
work reinvent ourselves try to
experiment try to do things which we've
never done
before and so these are some of the of
the
uh this is some of the output that we
have you know
um i realized then we started to create
some designs
uh during covid this was our challenge
was very difficult to do believe me
because it's hard for us designers to
come together to work with the craftsmen
to try to work with their hands
but these are just some of the few
designs that we were able to do
we know how important it is nowaday now
to stay outdoors but we can't so we
tried to bring the outdoors in
and part of the challenge was to create
these planters so
inspired by this beakers and instruments
that we used in chemistry
we did this this is called alchemy
and when you grow your own plant there
it's like having your own
little experiment inside hanging inside
your house this is the sage
it's a sofa that's inspired of course
obviously by a
big leaf and it's also similar to that
uh
story uh called thumbelina you know
and so this was the table that we tried
to put trees around it again part of our
part of the creative imaging uh these
of course again uh this is a the palm
chair
on the left is again a rendered setting
it's not real
no and on the right we tried to so these
are we tried to do our new storyboards
so we used this time when we could not
work
to just work on our on our online
presence on our catalogs
you know and this is a design of mine
also inspired by the movie up
yeah and so yeah so these are some of
the
uh these are um designs inspired by
islands where we
you know and it's great for social
distancing uh this is
called babar it's like a a big elephant
which we we um you know i've always
wanted to ride one
and then i turned it into an office a
small office space
actually the ears are like cork boards
you can open all the doors
you know and this is one of the last
designs i want to show you which we did
during during the pandemic um we
realized that people
may not be able to afford any more to
buy big pieces so we have to make small
pieces
and uh part of the challenge there was
to design like a jewelry stand
so we thought of of birds you know we
designed different birds and what if
these birds were holding all the jewelry
and resting on an on an island so we
started to make these birds we started
to make
mock-ups and this is the finished
product
it's made out of a porcelain it's a new
design called amelia
yeah and this is another small thing
that you did it's a clutch it's inspired
by those
you know the sabongeros who brought
their roosters inside their
little cages which they brought around
so i designed a clutch bag like that
yeah and that ends my presentations it's
been a challenge for us to stay creative
and resilient
i hope that by sharing with you this
this uh small
journey of mine you'll all be inspired
to also stay
creative resilient in whatever you do
so stay safe and strong thank you very
much
thank you
thank you very much mr cobenplay your cr
your creativity and the way that you
work with your team during this pandemic
are truly inspiring
and of course we will see more of you
and mr yap later
if you have questions to our dear guests
if you have questions you can always
just type it in in our q a box
and our speakers will answer it during
the panel session later
and now we will raffle off 3 000 pesos
worth of sodexo gift certificates
and let's see who our winner is
congratulations to miss sherry
congratulations you won 3 000 pesos
worth of sodexo gift certificate
a representative from mcbl will get in
touch with you on how you can claim your
prize
at this point we have heard practical
tips on how your business
can stay relevant for your employees and
customers
during this time our next speaker will
talk about how you can make your
business resilient regardless of
situation be it a pandemic or a loss of
a key officer in your company
she is a single law practitioner and
lecturer
with primary concentration on essay
planning
and settlement she's also an
award-winning author with five books
published
under her name ladies and gentlemen
please welcome
attorney victoria gilado
[Music]
good afternoon to all of you who took
the time to attend this webinar
it is a privilege to appear before you
together with mr richard yap
and mr kenneth copeland allow me to
greet manulife china bank life on this
important 13th anniversary and milestone
unfortunately this anniversary is being
celebrated during a pandemic
where all the rules for business and
social interaction have been turned
upside down
and we find ourselves living and working
in uncertain times
the taxing conditions we find ourselves
in demand that we take steps to protect
not only the people we love but also to
also to safeguard our businesses
and the people who run it an unusually
high number of people have been lost
during this pandemic
people who are crucial to the running of
any business
large and small as the pandemic has not
yet ended
tragically we may expect to continue to
lose people
the loss of which will have a
devastating impact on our businesses
this is precisely why manulife offers
schema
insurance a business tool which is
particularly relevant during the
pandemic
what is key man insurance keyman
insurance is a type of insurance taken
out by a company
on the life of key persons in its
organization
that's the term human insurance
unlike regular life insurance which most
people are familiar with
keyman insurance is purchased by a
company or a business
on the life of a key employee the
benefits paid out upon the laws of the
employee
are paid not to the family of the
employee but
to the company who purchased the key man
insurance next slide please
who are these key men in your business
well they are the usual suspects
the president the chief financial
officer the chief operating officer
heads of critical departments such as
your electronic data processing
human relations etc in a pharmaceutical
company it may be the head of research
and development
your chief chemist or your scientist in
a garment business
it may be your head designer or head
sower or even your beader or embroiderer
in a restaurant to pride itself with
having a michelin star or other
local or international recognition it
may be your chef
and even your maitre d in a hair salon
it would be the main hair and makeup
stylist and so forth
next slide please
after viewing the slides of kenneth and
returned and listening to both their
individual stories
on how they continue to weather the
pandemic it is clear that these two
persons are themselves examples of men
who are key to their business while they
are the most
critical persons in their companies they
are not the only key men
in their businesses kenneth is clearly
an artist and
the created brain behind the exceptional
furniture designs
perhaps he currently has an assistant
designer or
he may possibly consider training a
designer to stand in for him
when he decides to go on vacation or
even when he retires
so that his business can carry on
kenneth may engage the services of a new
graduate designer
who he will train over the years to
think and create like him
and who will help ease the load of his
business
kenneth may bring the head designer on
trips to attend the milan
furniture fair or other international
conventions
to expose him to the world of
international design
considerable expense and years are
involved in training canada's head
designer
but what would happen if kenneth's head
designer were to suddenly pass away
clearly the loss of his head designer
would be a severe blow to kenneth
on a personal level moreover there will
be an adverse impact on kenneth's
business
kenneth's company will have to search
for another person to replace
and train to be the head designer this
is no mean feat
in fact in countries like the united
kingdom apprenticeships are paid and
fought for
and involve years and years of training
and continued expense
this emphasizes the importance of key
people in an industry
who have acquired experience through
years of hard and expensive training
if kenneth had secured keyman insurance
on the life of his head designer the
keyman insurance paid out to kenneth's
company
will mitigate the disruption of the
business caused by the loss of the head
designer again
i hated to emphasize that monetary
benefits can never replace a lost life
the benefits derived from the key man
insurance may be utilized by the company
of
kenneth to engage the services of a
headhunter
to find the replacement designer of
equal caliber
to train the replacement to pay for the
trips abroad
to expose the trainee and even to
contribute to the salary of said
replacement
in the case of richard who has a chinese
restaurant business
he may have engaged the services of a
special chef
from china hong kong or taiwan who
specializes in one of the four major
chinese cuisines chuwan
previously richard may have traveled to
these countries and search off
and to interview and pick just the right
chef
again the sudden passing of the selected
chef would be a blow to research chinese
restaurant business
on the other hand if richard's company
had purchased the keyman
insurance policy on the life of his chef
the proceeds from the keyman insurance
will help richard pay the unexpected
expenses
of searching for a replacement chef for
the next travel expenses to hong kong
taiwan or mainland china and for the
training of said
chef next slide please
why else would a company secure keyman
insurance other than the cases i
mentioned earlier
next slide in cases where the key man is
so crucial to the business
and the business cannot continue without
him or her
the benefits will be will help in the
winding down of the business
of course the hope is always for the
business to be able to carry on despite
the loss
and without the key person in other
cases
substantial loans extended to companies
or in cases of mergers
the agreement may have provisions
requiring that the crucial key people
in the business are retained and that
keyman
insurance is obtained on their lives in
closing
while keema insurance cannot totally
replace a lost
valuable employee it can at the very
least
mitigate the effects of loss by
providing funds to the company
to assist in finding a replacement
paying the cost for the search for the
replacement
training the replacement and even to
give financial benefits to the family of
the employee who has passed away
i hope with this presentation that
you're able to recognize the value of
chemo
insurance as provided by manulife and
realize how crucial it is in the
pandemic times we find ourselves in
with that i will end my presentation
thank you we appreciate your insights on
keeping our businesses resilient
by ensuring that our vital personnel are
protected
before we proceed with our q a we would
like to acknowledge the presence of our
media friends and bloggers from national
broadsheets
blog sites and online news we have with
us today
abs-cbn business world
manila standard daily tribune
blueprint magazine lemon green tea
annaline.net thank you again for joining
us this afternoon and now
we are back this time with richard yap
kenneth corbin
and attorney gilado to answer some of
the questions that you've shared in our
q a box
so welcome back uh first we have a
question here
for attorney gilado attorney in the
absence of an
estate settlement plan what is the most
important document that we have to
prepare in case of an untimely demise
i think we have to make a distinction
when somebody speaks
of estate settlement talking of a person
who has passed away
and you are clearing the assets to be
transferred to the heirs
with the bir now if you're talking about
estate planning you're actually
considering
how to plan the distribution of your
your assets
to your heirs prior to your death in
answer to the question i i suppose the
question really is
what happens if you die without having a
plan
well if you don't have a plan the law
steps in
and will distribute your estate in
accordance with
preconceived ideas of what the law
thinks you would like to be done
however it is always best to prepare
one way to prepare is to make a will
however
it is expensive to make a will and it is
expensive to probate the will
under our laws all wells must be
probated
so you can actually achieve a more
tax efficient and a cheaper way to
settle your estate
if you were to plan it by making
donations during your lifetime
or in the case of the person who is
going to pass away
they may not care anymore because
they're not spending so they will just
pass away and let the law settle
whatever is at
issue thank you
it's really very important given all of
these things to really prepare
prior to anything happening right
okay um we all thank you for that
attorney we also have a question for mr
yap mr yap your restaurants
have shifted to digital cashless payment
and contactless deliveries
two major challenges when you shifted to
this strategy
well uh one of the major challenges was
that
we didn't have our own delivery team at
that time
so aside from using and collaborating
with grab food and food panda
and all these rider apps we also had to
create our own system of delivery
so that we would be able to augment
our delivery system um
aside from that since people were uh
shifting to cashless payments
there were major challenges because of
the unreliability of the bank
apps that we the people were using
sometimes the internet was not working
sometimes the apps were not working
um all their payments could not go
through
and um a lot of senior citizens were not
used to using technology
for paying online so um
we had to adjust um we're just so glad
that uh
um there are those apps like uh there
are those that
probably service that instead of paying
online
you can actually the rider will be able
to pay for you
and then when it arrives when it arrives
to the customer
then that's the time the customer can
pay the rider so that was also very
helpful for us but there are also
other means of paying now but mostly it
is online
so that was mostly the major challenges
were
on reliability of uh internet services
and the applications
but uh of course uh due to the other
systems that were being offered we got
through all this
i see thank you for that mr app and i
think even the customers are still
adjusting just for them to be able to
get the
services that you are offering outside
thank you for that
we have a question i think this is also
connected to the question that i have
for mr yap for
kenneth what were the major changes in
the import export trade that you
encountered during the pandemic
i think yeah it's okay now yeah
um yes it's the well everybody's been
affected of course
including of course uh the export
industry
um the good thing though i've noticed
was during towards the later parts
of months when people stayed at home
actually the whole market went up
because people started
to see what they were missing at home
you know and
that little light or that bed that they
put off you know they're now going to
buy because they're spending more time
in their houses and so this is uh
welcome actually
um for us because now people are
investing in their homes and
in fact i got a client who was saying
wow this lockdown is so expensive you
know because
now now we have to decorate we decorate
our homes you know i don't know if you
find the same thing
yeah they have the same experience yes
amazing yeah
um yeah but but hopefully like
everything else
it'll all improve no with uh we haven't
really stopped our
production since since the lockdown
right we've
gone on a skeletal force and now we're
trying to complete all our orders
is there any other
can you please tell us the story on how
your work ended up being featured in our
favorite k
dramas yeah actually i'm still trying to
figure that one out right because i
don't really watch kkk dramas except
people tell me it's there
it's here it's there it's here i think
it has to do with
our uh showroom in uh korea which is
located near gangnam area and uh
they have a lot of people
famous people from show business going
in and out of the showroom and they pick
out the pieces
which go towards these shows it's truly
an honor
to know that these pieces which are
crafted in cebu made in
philippines can go anywhere around the
world yeah
thank you and that's really something
that's a very something special
and um we have a question here for sir
richard you mentioned that you used to
be a franchise owner of chow king
um what have you learned from the
franchising experience
um well i guess uh if you're someone who
is
new to the business it's uh
it's a positive if you get a franchise
because you don't have to learn
everything yourself
um the company that you get the
franchise from will teach you everything
and it will show you the systems that
you need to get the business running
but there are also negative negative
effects if you franchise because
of course your costs are more expensive
rather than having your own
uh your own business but um
i guess it's just like you're paying for
tuition
so that you can you don't have to
relearn everything
because everything is taught to you
already you know
anything that's really the beauty of
franchisee heaven system that he can
just fall okay and then we have a
question here
for attorney gilado attorney are there
any changes
in the estate tax brought about by the
train law well
as you know the trade law took effect in
january 1
2018 and there were drastic changes
there
first of all the estate tax which used
to be as high as 20 percent
died to six percent and donor stocks
which used to be as high as
fifteen percent drove to six percent
so you could see that the government has
taken a lot of steps
in order to reduce these crucial taxes
which
a lot of people failed to pay in the
past because they were just too high
so right now we have the donor stocks
the capital gains tax and estimate tax
all
at six percent so this is an incentive
for people to pay
the right tax and to declare their
their assets uh or the assets of their
parents when they die
in particular the government also
is considering extending the estate tax
amnesty
where all the people who died prior to
december uh
31 2017 can avail of the lower tax rate
of six percent
based on the values of the properties at
the time of death
so if somebody died in 1940 and you
failed to settle the estate of your
grandfather
who owns the house you are living in you
can settle the essay of your grandfather
and pay a tax of 6 without any penalties
and based on the value of the property
in 1940.
so the government is considering
extending this for another two years
but it is still a bill which is spending
before the senate
thank you actually actually attorney
with
you with what you said i think everybody
who has a business really has to consult
somebody professional
to be able to address those kinds of
changes in the training right
so we have a special question here
actually from our manulife president and
ceo mr richard bates
um from this is for um
sir kenneth as a creatively minded
person who is running a large
company how do you segment your time
during the day to switch between
both roles so you're a creative
person and you're also at the same time
running your company
yeah um creative that's always been a
challenge that's actually a good
question
uh i think that creativity is like just
no different from any sport
it's no different from playing
basketball or
dancing or getting really good at
something you have to keep on doing
it and devoting a certain time for it so
i try to put
i fix a few hours of trying to come up
with something
every day and sometimes inspiration
comes sometimes
it it doesn't and then i just uh zone
out
in fact there's a lot of questions here
regarding that of how to stay inspired
what i do is i try to read a book uh
go online and watch a favorite movie try
to make myself happy
because if you're not happy you can't be
creative you can't be
inspired so that's really important that
your
your mindset is there and then
afterwards
um after that sometimes it's productive
sometimes it's not
but i devote that hour for creativity
and then afterwards then i go run
the the business so you need a really
good balance
both of uh i think of uh
in discipline both from uh creativity
and actually
uh running the business you know dealing
with people dealing with all the
problems
of the factory ac
okay so thank you for that um we have a
question here first
richard yeah this is this is really a
showbiz question
so since we are on the topic of
reinvention
as an actor how are you reinventing
yourself and your show basically
doing these things are there any new
projects that you can look forward to
um actually i just did the movie for uh
heaven's best entertainment um i don't
know when it's going to be shown
and i don't know where but uh they took
a chance
during this covid uh and we shot the
film
and we did it very well because nobody
got sick
um all the safety protocols were uh
were followed and we all got tested
before
and after also so that was adjusting to
this this covalent situation but
i guess in adjusting and reinventing
myself i
i guess we have to be uh
we have to adjust to what comes to new
roles and being flexible
um whether if i was known for doing
rom-com maybe
in the next next few months or next few
epis or next few projects i'll be doing
we might be doing some other things like
uh
uh action or being a contrabida
uh we have to be open to doing all these
things because
um i don't think we can just stick to
being something
that uh you cannot be stagnant we have
to
change ourselves all the time so i guess
uh
that is something that uh will depend
also on the on the offers of of the
networks that are offering
uh offering uh us
roles now
seeing you in a country be the role is
something that i have yet to see
and that's very interesting but i think
this question we have
we actually have so many questions
coming in today so
this is for everybody for all the
speakers
what do you do when you experience
burnouts or when you feel like your
creativity is drained so how do you
recharge um
can we how can we can we have uh the
uh attorney vicky what do you do
attorney when you
feel drained when i feel drained i watch
murder movies and detectives that gives
me
that perks me up more than anything else
uh
just detective movies
so it's really just um putting your your
mind away from what you are
working on and normally like when i
watch them i normally can tell who's
who's the murderer and so to me it's
also a bit of a challenge when i'm
watching those
i see so speaking of movies probably we
can we can
ask this question also to mr yap what do
you do when you're drained or when
you're burned out
actually this uh this pandemic has been
really draining for all of us i think a
lot of
people have been uh stressed out and
i guess i'm not you know i wasn't
spared from that also i was really
stressed out at one point that i really
didn't know what to do
because uh of course businesses were
shut down but we still had to play our
pay our suppliers and all that
uh what i did i just let go
and i prayed and uh i
to to lessen my stress i i you know i
just
worked out we went to my i have a home
gym so i
i go to the gym and work out so that i
can forget about all these things for a
while
but uh i guess prayer has a lot of of uh
playing the major part you know and
having the support of your family
so just let go for a while and think
about it
and or stop thinking about it and things
will just work themselves out
i see thank you for that mystery app and
yeah it's really it's just a matter of
trying to refocus and trying to get
strength from
um somebody higher than us so can we
have um
i i think this was also addressed by mr
corbin for ellip a while ago but
are there any other things that you do
when you feel drained when you feel
burned out
yes i tried to watch a richard yap fail
i richard and i richard and i
not many people know but we were
actually schoolmates uh in cebu
yeah oh ac yes uh we've been good
friends out
ever since and so i i i already i
already uh
answered that um a while ago so
yeah maybe we can move on to the next
question yeah i think we have a question
here as well for
both for mr yap and for mr cobin but
during the
uh this trying times when in person
interaction may still be limited how do
you maintain a connection with your
customers
um okay for us it's really
doing everything online um there are
people who
message us um through
whatever social media apps that we have
and that's
our way of uh you know we we try to
connect with them through that
by answering their questions answering
whatever concerns they have
um since you know face to face like like
usually
during mother's day i usually give out
roses and on
for our diners in wangfu but this year
we couldn't do that because of the
pandemic
so you know it's it's by
like uh we have i just do by something
by
like giving out messages on instagram or
facebook so that
at least will still be connected with
our customers
thank you for that um what about mr
coventry
well well for us since we're a worldwide
business right ninety percent of our
customers we really never
see i mean i personally don't see so
it's always been
in online so we still try to keep that
uh communication
going you know and uh yeah it's no
different
actually from what it was before before
call video because
uh yeah because of the nature of our
business
i see okay so they're really used to the
the online interaction already yes okay
we
we have a question here for mr yap
i think a lot are really into food
business right now so is it more
profitable to have your own delivery
service
versus just assigning the delivery
service to third party providers
um actually we we would rather have
other people do with like uh you know
the delivery services because
of course it meant setting up another
unit
in your business but uh at this time
we had no other choice but to do that
and in order to save the jobs
of the people who were working for us
also like the wait staff since they
weren't doing anything
now they have something to do at least
they have a salary
and they were able to earn a living so
it's now it was not a question of was it
is it going to be more uh
profitable if you have that or not but
it was a question of
trying to keep the business afloat and
trying to help these people
you know have still have their jobs and
have their income
you really get to see the concern for
people when you're working at this point
in time that
it's really the people that matters the
most and i can do that in
in the way you handle the team thank you
um
this question from the media um what
this is for everybody actually what were
your biggest learnings from the
challenges of this pandemic
um can we have attorney for for this
what's your biggest
learning from this pandemic right now i
think the fact that everybody's cooking
and making and selling is it's really
fantastic
people who never used to bake or cook
are
now into that business and you can see
the
entrepreneurial spirit of the filipino
and it's just something great to watch
thank you so yes a lot of people are now
expert cooks
and ex fruit and baking thank you for
that mr
coventry what's the major
learning that you yeah well i learned
two things i learned two things during
the pandemic
the first is that of course family and
relationships are so important
you know and when we when we're working
we tend to take them for granted
and now we find out that they're so we
were
actually reconnecting our relationships
and repairing mending
all their relationships and making them
richer and the second
i realized that by doing nothing you
know it seems
during the in the house it seems that
the days are so short the days fly by
very fast it's amazing because we always
think that
when we do nothing the days are so long
but you just find that there's not
enough time even when you're not doing
anything and so
it's made me realize that time is really
so so precious
and i think the hardest part for
everybody is how to go back to work
when we've been you know when we usually
wake up late in the mornings we sleep
early in the evenings and now
we have to go back again and have that
discipline to go back to work and keep
a strict you know job
yeah thank you for that uh mr rachel
yeah
what's your major learning during this
paragraph
i i really agree with what kenneth said
about family you know um
this has been a time for rediscovering
uh
you know because like he said when
you're
away working you'll sometimes you're not
even there when your kids are growing up
so this time has been very good for
everyone who has had the time to be with
their family
but uh it has also shown us that what
could be there today
can could also not be there tomorrow so
we have to
treasure everything that we have now um
everything has changed so much a lot of
businesses have closed down
so we are very thankful that we are
still surviving
and that is what really this year is all
about
you know that's what jack ma said uh
this year 2020 is really about survival
if your business can survive then maybe
we can get back to
normal normalcy in 2021
yes exactly thank you
thank you for that
that's all the um that we have for this
afternoon
i'd like to ask if you have final tips
for our guests today
so can we start with um mr yeah
um i guess uh what this has taught us is
that we have to work together with all
the stakeholders in our business which
means that
we work together with not only our
employees but also
with our landlords because in order for
us to survive we all have to give and
take
and we are very thankful that our
landlords have been very
uh helpful and um
they have been uh you know they have
given us the chance to be able to
survive this pandemic
by working together with us and
lessening our let's say our
lease on on on the
storefronts that we have and we have
also been collaborating with our
employees and they've been very
cooperative like they've been doing
other jobs aside from what they applied
for
and it has worked not only to benefit us
but also them
as well um we have we have to learn to
adjust adapt
and learn from what this pandemic has
given us
um has brought to us and we have to find
new ways of doing business
thank you thank you mr yave it's really
all about reinventing yourself right and
the business right now
um can you have final tips as well for
uh mr kenneth cobenplay
yeah this pandemic actually put a pause
in in all our lives and uh
we have to make the most out of it you
know it's taken
we've this has given us time to refresh
and think what we really want from our
lives
from our careers from our work and many
of us have discovered other things like
um
many have gone to uh cooking farming uh
growing anything to to survive and
perhaps there we find our passion
we find other things that we never knew
we were good at and this is one way of
looking at this uh
pandemic you know instead of something
very negative as a time for us to just
pause and rethink you know rethink our
businesses
our own lives our relationships and put
them in the right
direction
[Music]
okay thank you and of course last but
not the least
let's hear from attorney gilado
thank you you know my family has been
very fortunate during this
pandemic we have not been
critically affected and with the
with the good fortune comes a deep
realization
that there are so many who need so much
help
i recall one of the janitors in in our
office
he had been requesting for assistance so
but i recall one day when he told me uh
he was asking for help again
and he told me that he had walked seven
hours to get to his janitorial job
in taguig only because there was no
public transportation and when he told
me the story that he had left 100 pesos
with his family
because that was the only amount of
money he had left and he walked
seven hours to get the gig from i think
it was from
i really couldn't imagine how difficult
it must have been for somebody like him
and and we see on our daily on a daily
basis so many people
struggling and not it's it's not only
enough that they
they are really going lower than what
this
has they've ever experienced so i think
it is the time now that people will have
so much should give
even if it hurts because they hurt more
than you
and that's all
thank you for that attorney it's really
us helping each other out during this
time of pandemic
it's not just um keeping our ourselves
our families and our businesses afloat
but everybody
now going through this together so that
we'll be able to face a better 2021
in the future okay so thank you once
again
kenneth richard and attorney vicky it
was indeed a very very insightful
afternoon
i hope our guests are still with us
because we will now be raffling off
5 000 pesos worth of sodexo gift
certificates to one lucky registrant so
let's see
congratulations to
mr allen lee a representative from mcbl
will get in touch with you on how you
can claim your prize
to officially close this afternoon's
webinar
we have with us manulife china bank's
president
and ceo mr sandeep de obacta
thank you for joining us in this
afternoon's webinar
we hope you enjoyed it we're thankful
for the trust you've given us
and please know that we stay committed
to making every day better for you
we want to ensure that you have access
to our financial solutions
and that your needs are properly
addressed our financial sales associates
are available to assist you
especially during these times once again
thank you once again and sandeep and to
our attendees thank you very much for
spending your afternoon with us
we'd like to hear your feedback on this
afternoon's webinar so please
simply scan the qr code on screen and
answer
our two-minute survey yes i brought
should you have any questions on the
discussions today
please feel free to get in touch with
the china bank or mcbl personal
who invited you to this webinar this has
been your host
ronnie austria thanking you once again
for joining us this afternoon
we hope to see you in our future
webinars in the meantime stay safe
[Music]
do
manulife and china bank
two companies you can trust two top
institutions in the financial industry
teammates partners working together to
handle every aspect of your finances
from day to day to your future plans
personalized to your story
so you're ready for life's every twist
and turn
we have you covered starting with your
kids dreams
to providing a secure future for your
family
working to build your wealth and
ensuring your wealth
works for you always with you in
sickness and in health
through the best times and the worst all
just for you
let us be your partner manulife china
bank life
life with a plan let us help you get
started
today
1920.
here 100 years ago men
of courage and vision founded china bank
to help a community of struggling but
worthy merchants and traders
achieve their dreams
[Music]
they were driven by an impeccable code
of trust
and respect through the hard times
and the good times that's how
china bank successfully partnered with
four
five generations of loyal clients
today china pack keeps pace with
evolving technology
while remaining grounded on integrity
and prudence
china back celebrating the past
embracing the future times change
but values remain
what makes an organization successful
is it being a top player in sales and
market share
acquiring new customers or generating a
healthy
income and net profit it's no secret
that to achieve all of these a company
needs its most valuable asset
people most businesses have one
or more senior personal whose experience
skills and knowledge are vital to
achieving company goals
losing them can have adverse effects
including
missing company targets investing
in human and monetary resources to find
a replacement
and reduced confidence among
stakeholders
like investors partners and customers
one solution to protect your business
from all of these
is key man insurance but what exactly
is a key man insurance a key man
is someone who contributes significant
service or
talent to the organization and its
customers
and a key man insurance protects you
against the sudden loss of this
key person by providing enough liquidity
to ensure continuity of business and
aiding the company
and recovering from the loss many firms
ensure their premises
equipments and goods against fire
theft and flood but many missed the
opportunity
to insure their company against the loss
of key people
who helped run it successfully manulife
china
bank life can provide you with the
innovative key man solutions
to serve your company's needs with key
man insurance
will protect your company from the
possible loss of your key people
to ensure your continued success
contact manulife china bank life now
to help you get started
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
do
you